empoweringparents.com 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy - Empowering Parents

#### _Effective as of April 12, 2019_

We want you to feel secure when visiting the EmpoweringParents.com web site (the “Web Site”) and are committed to maintaining your privacy when doing so. Please take a moment to read this Privacy Policy, which describes the online data collection and usage policies and practices that apply to the Web Site. By using the Web Site, you consent to the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with these policies and practices, please discontinue your use of the Web Site.

This Web Site is made available by the Advantage Media Group (DBA “EmpoweringParents.com”), and all references herein to “we” or “us” refer to EmpoweringParents.com. All references herein to “you” or “user” refers to any person that accesses and/or uses the Web Site.

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our Web Site so that you can always find out what information we gather, and how we might use that information. We encourage you to periodically review our Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are using the personal information we collect. Your continued use of this Web Site after any changes have been posted constitutes your agreement to the changes.

### INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

#### Personal Information

In some areas of our Web Site, we may request that you provide personal information, including your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, and any other information from which your identity is discernable (“personal information”). If you place an order through our online store, we will ask you to provide credit, debit, or other financial account information as well as your contact and billing information. Other examples of pages where we may collect personal information are pages where you complete an online registration form to participate in any blog feature or discussion forum made available through the Web Site, register to receives our e-mail newsletters, or submit a question through the “Contact” link on the Web Site.

#### Sharing Personal Information

We may disclose personal information to contractors or service providers that help us provide services to you or deliver products or services to you. For example, we may disclose your billing information to payment processors to process fee payments or other financial transactions; we may disclose your shipping address to fulfillment and shipping contractors to deliver a product to you; and, we may disclose your email address to email fulfillment contractors to send you emails from us. We may share your personal information with other reputable organizations for their marketing purposes.

We may share some or all of your personal information with our subsidiaries and affiliates, joint venturers, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “affiliates”), in which case we will require these affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will possess the personal information collected by us and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may disclose personal information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual prohibited activities, including without limitation, fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person or violations of EmpoweringParents.com’s Terms of Use.

#### Non-Personally-Identifiable Information

We may collect non-personally-identifiable information about your computer and navigation patterns. When you visit our sites, our systems may automatically note your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your computer’s operating system, the browser you use for Internet access, and the specific web pages visited during your connection. We may also track data such as the total number of visits to the Web Site, and the number of visitors to each page of the Web Site.

We may use non-personally-identifiable information to determine which pages you visit, and in what order your visit them, in order to help us improve our sites. We may also use non-personally-identifiable information in aggregate form for system maintenance and to better understand how our visitors use our site and services so that we can make them better. We may share statistical or demographic information in aggregate form with third parties for marketing or research purposes. This aggregate data will not contain any personal information.

#### California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of EmpoweringParents.com who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding twelve calendar months. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:

Empowering Parents  
325 Main Street  
Suite 114  
Waterville ME 04901  
(800) 460-2253  
service@empoweringparents.com

EmpoweringParents.com may make your personal information available to third parties for their marketing purposes as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not wish to share your personal information in this way, send your request to:

Empowering Parents  
325 Main Street  
Suite 114  
Waterville ME 04901  
(800) 460-2253  
service@empoweringparents.com

#### European Union Privacy

For citizens of the European Union, the law states that we can store cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site. For all other types of cookies we need your permission.

You can at any time change or withdraw your consent from the [Cookie Policy](https://www.empoweringparents.com/cookie-policy/) page on our website.

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you have the following rights:

The right to be informed – this means anyone processing your personal data must make clear what they are processing, why, and who else the data may be passed to.

The right of access – this is your right to see what data is held about you by us.

The right to rectification – the right to have your data corrected or amended if what is held is incorrect in some way.

The right to erasure – under certain circumstances you can ask for your personal data to be deleted. This is also called ‘the Right to be Forgotten’. This would apply if the personal data is no longer required for the purposes it was collected for, or your consent for the processing of that data has been withdrawn, or the personal data has been unlawfully processed.

The right to restrict processing – this gives you the right to ask for a temporary halt to processing of personal data, such as in the case where a dispute or legal case has to be concluded, or the data is being corrected.

The right to data portability – you have the right to ask for any data supplied directly to us by you, to be provided in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format.

The right to object – you have the right to object to further processing of your data which is inconsistent with the primary purpose for which it was collected, including profiling, automation, and direct marketing.

Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling – you have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing.

If you have any concerns or questions regarding how we process your data, or if you wish to exercise any rights you have under the GDPR, please contact us at:

Empowering Parents  
325 Main Street  
Suite 114  
Waterville ME 04901  
(800) 460-2253  
service@empoweringparents.com

#### Children’s Privacy

This Web Site is intended for adults. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. However, if the parent or guardian of a child under 13 believes that the child has provided us with personal information, the parent or guardian of that child should contact us if they want this information deleted from our files. If we otherwise obtain knowledge that we have personal information about a child under 13 in its files, we will delete that information from our existing files so that it is not in retrievable form.

### DATA SECURITY

We have implemented reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss, and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, or disclosure. We use technology, controls and restrictions on employee access to help safeguard your personal information. The credit card information or other account information that you input at the time of purchase is protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology for secure communications. If your browser does not support SSL, or if you do not want to send your credit card information via the web, please contact us.

Notwithstanding our data security procedures, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be completely secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control, and we cannot absolutely guarantee the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information exchanged between you and us through this Web Site. We make no warranty, express, implied, or otherwise, that we will prevent unauthorized access to your personal information.

### PRIVACY POLICIES OF THIRD PARTIES

When you use our Web Site, you may interact with or link to third parties that operate their own web sites and have their own privacy policies. Also, companies with whom we share your information have their own privacy policies. Other companies that may place advertisements on our sites may collect information about you through the use of cookies when you view or click on their advertising. We are not responsible for the policies and practices of these third parties.

### USE OF COOKIES AND TAGGING

Like many commercial websites, we analyze how readers use this site through what is known as “cookie” technology. A “cookie” is a small text file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie is not an app or program and has no ability to read the data residing on your computer. We cannot instruct it to execute functions or take any actions. Cookies do not provide us with any personal data or information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

Similarly, we use what is known as “client-side page tagging” to write certain information about the page and the visitor to a log when a page is rendered by your web browser. This technique is also commonly used on commercial websites. “Tagging” does result in a small amount of JavaScript running on your computer, but it is limited to providing information about the page that you are requesting and the configuration of your browser. It will not read any of your data files, or execute any additional programs. It does not extract any personal information about you, such as your name or address. You can prevent tagging by disabling JavaScript in your browser, but that may prevent you from using all of our website’s functions.

You can learn more about the cookies in use on our website on our [Cookie Policy](https://www.empoweringparents.com/cookie-policy/) page.

### DATA SECURITY

We use tools from Google, Adobe and others to help collect aggregate data, such as browser type, connection speed, referring/exit pages, device type, date/time stamp, and the number of clicks to help us analyze trends, administer the site and make improvements. This information is not linked to any personally identifiable information you may share with us.

Google and Adobe may also provide anonymous information about your visits to this and other websites (such as age and gender) to help us improve the content on our web site, refine our products and provide information about our other products and services that might be of interest to you.

You can obtain more information about this practice and to identify your choices about not having this information used by Google and Adobe from their respective web sites. You can opt-out of cookie-based tracking at any time by simply clearing your browser’s cookie cache or activating your web browser’s “do not track” function.

We may partner with advertising networks who serve ads on behalf of us and others on non-affiliated sites. Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to you based on information advertising networks collect about your visits to this site and elsewhere over time. You may also visit www.aboutads.info to learn more about this type of advertising and how to opt-out of this form of advertising by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) self-regulatory program. Note that electing to opt out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. In addition, note that if you use a different browser or erase cookies from your browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.

### HOW YOU CAN ACCESS OR CORRECT INFORMATION

To access the personal information that this site has collected about you, to correct factual errors in such information, or to update any portions of your user profile, please contact us using the contact information below.

### CONTACT US

Empowering Parents  
325 Main Street  
Suite 114  
Waterville ME 04901  
(800) 460-2253  
service@empoweringparents.com
